Luke Olawale

💡 74 11 crescent, Kado Estate, 900108 Abuja, Nigeria 🛛 🖂 lukeolawale4@gmail.com 📞 +2348031894288

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/luke-olawale/

Profile

Dedicated and efficient full stack developer with 1+ years experience in developing scalable web applications and working across the full stack. I am looking to join forces with a global company to continue to grow my skill set while contributing to the positive outcome of making people "richer, smarter, and happier."

Professional Experience

11/2021 - present Abuja, Nigeria

Full Stack Developer

YourRider Limited

- Help the software support team adjust programming to solve production issues.
- Provided guidance regarding advertising, product development, and product placement.

09/2021 - present Abuja, Nigeria

Azure Infrastructure and Security Engineer,

Lotus Beta Analytics Nigeria Limited

- Deployed Azure App Services
- Azure Backup Solution Setup.
- Azure VM Setup & Configuration.
- configure VM Instance Monitoring & mail alert via Azure
- Monitor.

02/2020 - 08/2020 Abuja, Nigeria

Junior IT Specialist

Lotus Beta Analytics Nigeria Limited

- Deployment of Microsoft Windows Virtual Desktop.
- Deployment of Microsoft 365 Packages.
- Server migration from on-premises to cloud.

12/2019 - 02/2020 Abuja, Nigeria

Graduate Intern,

Meed Networks Nigeria Limited

- Website development.
- Installed finger Tec Ingressus device with motion detector and fire alarm.
- Worked with professionals on networking problems, fiber network installation, and troubleshooting.

04/2018 - 12/2018

Intern

Abuja, Nigeria

Meed Renewable Nigeria Limited

- Worked with professionals on installation of solar panels, solar batteries and inverters.
- Installation of network radio devices.

Education

06/2022 - 10/2022

Full Stack Web Developer

Udacity

- SQL and Data Modeling for the Web
- API Development and Documentation
- Identity Access Management
- Server Deployment and Containerization

09/2014 - 12/2019

Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng.) Electrical

Zaria, Nigeria

Ahmadu Bello University Zaria

Graduated with second-class honors upper division.

06/2022 - 07/2023

Software Engineering

Holberton School - ALX Africa

- Introduction to Emacs Vim Git/Github
- C programming basics, function, pointers, data structures, lists, arrays memory management, file redirection and printf.
- Linux basics, permissions and redirections.
- Static Libraries

Skill

• HTML ,CSS and React knowledge | C, PostgreSQL, Angular and Python skills | Mobile-responsive design | Intermediate experience with JavaScript | Teamwork | Communication | Problem-solving

Projects

Personal Landing Page

www.lukeshub.site

Client Site: Teleconnect Outsource Limited

www.teleconnectoutsource.com

Client Site: Precision Info Tech Limited

www.precisioninfotech.com

Artist Booking Site

www.hellogreen.ng

Certificates

- Microsoft Certified: Power Platform Developer Associate
- Microsoft Certified: Information Protection Administrator Associate
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate
- Microsoft Certified: Security Operations Analyst Associate
- Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Certified Architect Professional.
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Security Engineer Associate